Hello everyone, in this video, we will introduce the GPU simulation optimization content of Marvelous Designer 2024.2.
In this update, the GPU simulation conflict processing has been greatly improved.
This jacket is made up of a large number of panels, and the particle diameter of the panel is 5.
When dragging the panel, there is no problem of layer intersection, and the simulation is stable and effective.
Compared to the 2024.2 version
In the previous version
The GPU simulation preset in Marvelous Designer 2024.2 is limited when dealing with conflicts between multiple layers of panels.
You can see that there is a partial overlap or overlap between some panels.
In the 2024.2 version, the simulation of this suit is more stable and the simulation results are more reasonable.
Now let's take a look at the update of the simulation menu.
First of all, in the simulation type, the animation of the new animation used to record the cloth animation is completed.
In addition, at the bottom of the simulation type, the option of changing the CPU or GPU simulation is added.
Now when choosing the various simulation types, you can choose to use the CPU or GPU to complete the simulation.
Use the GPU to do the simulation of the various simulations.
The icon that the simulation preset is empty-cast.
In the previous version, the results of CPU simulation and GPU simulation were significantly different.
From the 2024.2 version, we improved the accuracy of the GPU simulation to make the GPU simulation and CPU simulation almost identical.
Now through the updated GPU simulation, you can increase the efficiency of the work and get the same excellent simulation result.
Next, let's compare the actual GPU simulation with the CPU simulation.
Let's compare the GPU simulation with the CPU simulation.
If you look at the data statistics in the bottom left corner of the 3D window, you can see the relevant data of the version and the FPS rate.
In the video, these versions have a peak value of more than 110,000.
Let's choose the default default setting to simulate first.
On the left is the GPU simulation effect, and on the right is the CPU simulation effect. This video is not accelerated.
You can see that although there is a huge difference in speed, the final simulation results are almost the same.
Then let's look at the simulation effect of the material attribute calculation type in Sichuan.
The GPU simulation is also faster.
This simulation setting will activate the precise material shrinkage simulation in the simulation attribute.
In this way, you can get a more accurate simulation result, and the clothing will be more close to the effect in real life.
Finally, let's test the animation simulation preset.
You can see that the GPU simulation is still much faster than the CPU simulation.
The animation has completed the preset.
You can use it to simulate a more smooth and stable cloth animation.
Now let's test the conflict processing function of the GPU simulation.
Although it is now a three-layer version, the simulation can still be completed very smoothly.
You can see that the GPU simulation is still much faster than the CPU simulation.
One of the advantages of using GPU simulation is that it can significantly improve the efficiency of work when processing low-chloride-resistant panels.
Now, let's test the GPU simulation.
Let's start the simulation and check the simulation effect under the influence of the wind.
Here, the video is not accelerated. You can see the actual simulation effect.
Although there are many peak points in the grid, the wind-blow effect is still very fast.
You can see that the GPU simulation is much faster than the CPU simulation.
The wind-blow effect is also faster than the CPU simulation.
Thank you.
The GPU simulation will also save you work time and improve efficiency.
The video shows the real-time recording effect without acceleration.
Because the speed of the GPU simulation will be different depending on the graphics card you use,
but in general, the GPU simulation has a significant improvement in speed compared to the CPU simulation.
This is because the GPU simulation methods are now being updated.
Thank you.
Please note that GPU simulation can not be applied to close-up resolution and software model simulation for the time being.
In the previous version, the simulation information will be recorded in the project file, but from this version, the GPU simulation information will not be stored in the costume project file or the simulation attribute setting file.
Thanks for watching.
Please click the like button if you like this video.
Next we'll take a look at the GPU simulation manager.
Thank you for watching, see you in the next video!
Thanks for watching!